

AAMIR ABDULSALAM

Service Delivery Specialist/ Application Support Engineer

P Bengaluru, KA

**** +919995110466

☑ aamir.salam5@gmail.com

Skills

Linux

RHEL 7, Solaris, AIX, Shell Scripting

Oracle DBMS

Oracle 10G,11G,12C,OEM,RMAN

SQL/PL SQL

Troubleshooting, Problem solving, Complex querying

Windows Server

Performance Management, IIS, IAM, Active Directory

Network Troubleshooting

TCP/IP, DNS, DHCP etc

Customer/ End User Interaction

B2B, Technical Support

Cloud

AWS

Incident Management

Service Now, HPSM, Tivoli

Certification

ITIL v3 Foundation (Certified by IBM)

Summary

Service Delivery Specialist/ Technical Engineer with 6.5 years of experience in Service Delivery management, IT Operations, Oracle Database

Management/Development and Technical Support, all technically focused as well as customer oriented. Achieved smooth delivery for clients by collaborating with multiple service lines. Created vital metrics for performance estimation, highlighting achievements, goals and improvement on gaps.

Work experience

2018-05 - Application Support Engineer

2020-04 Emirates Airlines, Dubai

- Responsible for managing and supporting the infrastructure of Critical application to ensure seamless operation.
- System administration tasks performed on Linux RHEL servers and Windows Servers for health checks, user management and business and technical incident requests.
- Provided technical assistance for enterprise solutions and AWS cloud services.
- Developed organizational units in Active Directory (AD) and managed user security with group policies.
- Troubleshoot build issues in Jenkins, performance and generating metrics on master's performance along with jobs usage.
- Provided TIBCO middleware support to track, manage volume capacity.

 Monitoring problem queues and utilizing wellness check scripts and resolute issues as they arise during operation.
- Informatica Powercenter Administration to analyze, monitor and troubleshoot scheduled ETL job runs and engage stakeholders from business or technical areas in case of disruptions.
- Use SQL and PL SQL developer to analyze and troubleshoot data quality within database and interface tables, procedures and packages.
- Identity and Access Management tasks performed to ensure that respective users and user groups have the appropriate system access to enterprise apps.
 Tools used such as syslog-ng and other internal applications.
- Maintained close collaboration with vendors to ensure timely support whenever necessary.
- Managed incidents with Service-Now adhering to ITIL standards and resolving high severity incidents without breach of SLA. Involved with reporting monthly incident reports to tackle trending problem areas.

2016-01 - System Administrator/ Service Delivery Specialist

2018-01 IBM India

- Responsible for managing and supporting all Production and Development instances of Oracle 10g & 11g.
- Coordinated and worked on Incident management on a daily basis along with Problem and Change management workload.
- Helped to improve the performance, scalability and stability of database systems.
- Unix/Linux/Windows systems administrator with experience configuring, monitoring, upgrading and maintaining systems software and related infrastructure
- Strong analytical skills; able to work with technicians from various engineering disciplines to troubleshoot complex system-level issues.
- Troubleshoot and resolve database and/or application problems encountered by end users.
- Provide on-call and 24x7 support in adherence to specific business and customer Service Level Agreements.

2014-01 - Senior Technical Support Engineer

2016-01 IBM India

- Provided daily application and technical support for email, network, connectivity, telecommunications, peripheral equipment and system maintenance.
- $\bullet\,$ Research client's issues in a timely manner and follow up with the customer with

recommendations and action plans for internal and vendor support.

- Responsible for creation of customer service metrics and explaining metrics to management.
- Trained with senior system engineers to enhance my personal technical skills as
 a Technical Support Engineer and learned internal processes for escalating
 cases and approving or denying handovers to specific verticals.
- Troubleshoot and configure applications, provide network connection support, as well as customer input to the ticketing system.
- Mentored new engineers by answering technical questions, escalating cases, and teaching detailed process development.
- Work efficiently in queues (email and self-service) that require a SLA time goal.

2013-02 -2013-08

E-Commerce Administrator

International Marketing Services, Dubai

- Provided daily application and technical support for email, network, connectivity, telecommunications, peripheral equipment and system maintenance.
- Research client's issues in a timely manner and follow up with the customer with recommendations and action plans for internal and vendor support.
- Responsible for creation of customer service metrics and explaining metrics to management.
- Trained with senior system engineers to enhance my personal technical skills as
 a Technical Support Engineer and learned internal processes for escalating
 cases and approving or denying handovers to specific verticals.
- Troubleshoot and configure applications, provide network connection support, as well as customer input to the ticketing system.
- Mentored new engineers by answering technical questions, escalating cases, and teaching detailed process development.
- Work efficiently in queues (email and self-service) that require a SLA time goal.

Education

2008 - 2012

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology

TKM Institute of Technology

Skills

Operating System : RHEL, Sun Solaris, AIX, Linux, Windows Server

Languages : SQL,PL SQL

Middleware : TIBCO 5.1

Cloud Platform : AWS (EC2,ELB,RDS,S3,Cloudwatch)

RDBMS : Oracle10g/11g, SQL Server 2012

ETL : Informatica Powercenter

Tools : Oracle SQL Developer, Syslog-ng, , MS AD, IIS 7.5

Devops Tool : Jenkins, Git, Maven

Ticketing tool : IBM SCCD, Tivoli Maximo, Service-Now

References

Abdulla Qassim, Managing Director, International Marketing Service, Dubai, UAE
Karthikeyan Jayapalan, Technical Service Manager, IBM India Pvt Ltd, Bangalore, India
Manju Tharakan, Incident Manager, Emirates Airlines, Dubai, UAE